<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>COVID-19 | West 136th Block Assoc</title>
    <link>/tag/covid-19/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/covid-19/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>COVID-19</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 21:32:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>COVID-19</title>
      <link>/tag/covid-19/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Update</title>
      <link>/post/2020-04-04-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 21:32:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-04-04-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Hi Neighbors,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please see info below regarding free meals and free wifi. Distribute as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be safe and stay well,&lt;br /&gt;
-Candi Halbert&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I. FACE MASKS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Mayor Bill De Blasio asked all New Yorkers to wear a face covering when they go outside in the public. He cited research showing asymptomatic people could be spreading the virus without realizing it. “When you put on that face covering, you’re protecting everyone else,” he said. As I said in my prior email, &lt;strong&gt;When you wear your mask, you protect me. When I wear my mask, I protect you&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.japanesecreations.com/no-sew-face-mask-with-handkerchief-and-hair-tie&#34;&gt;Click Here&lt;/a&gt; for a DIY &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.japanesecreations.com/no-sew-face-mask-with-handkerchief-and-hair-tie&#34;&gt;no-sew mask option&lt;/a&gt; using an ordinary handkerchief and rubber bands/hair ties as well as substitutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;II. FREE MEALS HUB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Any New Yorker who wants a free meal can now get meals every Monday thru Friday at any of 400+ Meal Hubs across NYC.
Anyone can pick up three free, to-go meals at one time. All sites offer vegetarian &amp;amp; halal options. No ID required.
Find a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.schools.nyc.gov/school-life/food/free-meals&#34;&gt;Meal Hub&lt;/a&gt; here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.schools.nyc.gov/school-life/food/free-meals&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://www.schools.nyc.gov/school-life/food/free-meals&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;III. COVID-19 IN NYC: CONFIRMED CASES NEAR YOU&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
New York City leads the U.S. in the number of confirmed coronavirus cases, with more than 45,000 residents testing positive, according to city statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.propublica.org/graphics/covid-nyc&#34;&gt;CLICK HERE&lt;/a&gt; to look up your ZIP code to see how your neighborhood compares to the rest of the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of March 31, 3.5 per thousand people who live in the 10030 ZIP code have tested positive for COVID-19, which is 25% lower than the city average. In total, 106 of the 204 people tested had a positive result. Note: Only a small number of people are tested, so the actual number of positive cases is much higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://patch.com/new-york/harlem/harlem-coronavirus-cases-city-releases-data-zip-code?utm_term=article-slot-1&amp;amp;utm_source=newsletter-daily&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=newsletter&#34;&gt;Harlem Coronavirus Cases By Zip Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IV. FREE INTERNET ACCESS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://corporate.comcast.com/covid-19&#34;&gt;Xfinity WiFi Free For Everyone&lt;/a&gt;:
Xfinity WiFi hotspots located in businesses and outdoor locations across the country will be available to anyone who needs them for free – including non-Xfinity Internet subscribers. For a map of Xfinity WiFi hotspots, visit www.xfinity.com/wifi Once at a hotspot, consumers should select the “xfinitywifi” network name in the list of available hotspots and then launch a browser. Go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://corporate.comcast.com/covid-19&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://corporate.comcast.com/covid-19&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spectrum:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.businessinsider.com/coronavirus-free-spectrum-internet-wifi-offer-student-households-promotion-2020-3&#34;&gt;Free Access to Spectrum Broadband&lt;/a&gt; For 60 Days For New K-12 and College Students
To enroll call 1-844-488-8395. Installation fees will be waived for new student households.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Altice:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.alticeusa.com/news/articles/feature/corporate/altice-usa-brings-free-broadband-k-12-and-college-students-during-coronavirus-pandemic&#34;&gt;Altice USA Brings Free Broadband to K-12 and College Students During Coronavirus Pandemic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V. Other community resources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gcc01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fdocs.google.com%2Fdocument%2Fd%2F1TMcuBSpECMODwylVlJDl0Urooi0x-3C34O0ukLz_PEs%2Fmobilebasic&amp;amp;data=02%7C01%7CSMitchell%40cb.nyc.gov%7Cb8ad65cacd7f41492bd008d7d7d3b04c%7C32f56fc75f814e22a95b15da66513bef%7C0%7C0%7C637215176502745368&amp;amp;sdata=%2B2g5iQLsEPSOVTY06OAMy%2FGyXgyBb3AyUd1LOjhDvlw%3D&amp;amp;reserved=0&#34;&gt;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1TMcuBSpECMODwylVlJDl0Urooi0x-3C34O0ukLz_PEs/mobilebasic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masks4All</title>
      <link>/post/2020-03-31-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 13:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-03-31-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Hi Neighbors!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope everyone is well and that we all continue in good health as our block, Harlem, the city and the country faces the COVID-19 pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As if it needs to be said, please heed the strong recommendation to practice social distancing, limit social interaction, and generally STAY HOME.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to share some data and advice I’ve given to my family and friends based on research, not fear. I strongly encourage everyone to wear some sort of mask in your everyday life when you are out in public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mask &lt;strong&gt;does NOT&lt;/strong&gt; need to be the coveted &lt;strong&gt;N95&lt;/strong&gt; masks and research has shown that a simple bandana across your nose and mouth will provide some benefit. So this recommendation has &lt;strong&gt;no impact on hospital workers&lt;/strong&gt; or other front-line workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In simple terms, when you sneeze, cough, talk, or even breathe, you expel tiny droplets from your respiratory tract. Sneezing, coughing, talking, or even breathing by an infected individual can transmit the virus onto surfaces or into the air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By wearing a mask you reduce the transmission of infected respiratory droplets. Since some people can be infected and show no symptoms, it just makes sense for everyone to wear a mask. &lt;strong&gt;When you wear your mask, you protect me. When I wear my mask, I protect you&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if you don’t have a mask or have run out of masks and the shortage prevents you from getting one? There are several Youtube tutorials for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iNX0cRrYj6U&#34;&gt;homemade masks.&lt;/a&gt; Even simpler is this tutorial using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pJaVBt8q6g8&#34;&gt;an old T-shirt requiring NO sewing&lt;/a&gt;. Finally, a simple scarf or bandana can also be used. As a point of comparison, a surgical mask is 89% effective in filtering virus particles as small as the COVID-19 where a simple T-shirt or scarf can be 50% effective.[*]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For additional insights, &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/BoDwXwZXsDI&#34;&gt;video by USF Data Scientist Jeremy Howard&lt;/a&gt; and his Washington Post article titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/outlook/2020/03/28/masks-all-coronavirus/&#34;&gt;‘Simple DIY masks could help flatten the curve. We should all wear them in public’&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be well,&lt;br /&gt;
-Candi Halbert&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research Papers…&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2440799/&#34;&gt;1. Professional and Home-Made Face Masks Reduce Exposure to Respiratory Infections among the General Population&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3074351/coronavirus-can-travel-twice-far-official-safe-distance-and-stay&#34;&gt;2. Coronavirus can travel twice as far as official ‘safe distance’, study says&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/disaster-medicine-and-public-health-preparedness/article/testing-the-efficacy-of-homemade-masks-would-they-protect-in-an-influenza-pandemic/0921A05A69A9419C862FA2F35F819D55&#34;&gt;3. Testing the Efficacy of Homemade Masks: Would They Protect in an Influenza Pandemic? | Disaster Medicine and Public Health Preparedness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cebm.net/what-is-the-efficacy-of-standard-face-masks-compared-to-respirator-masks-in-preventing-covid-type-respiratory-illnesses-in-primary-care-staff/&#34;&gt;4. What is the efficacy of standard face masks compared to respirator masks in preventing COVID-type respiratory illnesses in primary care staff?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMc2004973&#34;&gt;5. Aerosol and Surface Stability of SARS-CoV-2 as Compared with SARS-CoV-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://stanfordmedicine.app.box.com/v/covid19-PPE-1-1&#34;&gt;6. Addressing COVID-19 Face Mask Shortages: evaluating decontamination methods for N95 mask reuse.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lanres/article/PIIS2213-2600(20)30134-X/fulltext&#34;&gt;7. Rational use of face masks in the COVID-19 pandemic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3591312/&#34;&gt;8. Influenza Virus Aerosols in Human Exhaled Breath: Particle Size, Culturability, and Effect of Surgical Masks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29140516/&#34;&gt;9. Effectiveness of Masks and Respirators Against Respiratory Infections in Healthcare Workers: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6993921/&#34;&gt;10. Physical interventions to interrupt or reduce the spread of respiratory viruses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/pdf/10.1111/jebm.12381&#34;&gt;11. Effectiveness of N95 respirators versus surgical masks against influenza: A systematic review and metaâ•’analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/risa.13181&#34;&gt;12. Modeling the Effectiveness of Respiratory Protective Devices in Reducing Influenza Outbreak&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
